[
  {
    "question": "Who is the current President of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Arif Alvi",
      "Asif Ali Zardari",
      "Mamnoon Hussain",
      "Pervez Musharraf"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Arif Alvi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which party won the majority in the 2018 general elections in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)",
      "Pakistan Muslim League (N)",
      "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)",
      "Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the current Prime Minister of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Imran Khan",
      "Shehbaz Sharif",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Benazir Bhutto"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Shehbaz Sharif"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known as the 'City of Lights'?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi",
      "Lahore",
      "Islamabad",
      "Rawalpindi"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karachi"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year was Pakistan's last general election held?",
    "options": [
      "2018",
      "2013",
      "2008",
      "2003"
    ],
    "correctOption": "2018"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani political leader was ousted from office in a no-confidence vote in 2022?",
    "options": [
      "Imran Khan",
      "Shehbaz Sharif",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Asif Ali Zardari"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Imran Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the Chief of Army Staff of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "General Syed Asim Munir",
      "General Qamar Javed Bajwa",
      "General Raheel Sharif",
      "General Ashfaq Pervez Kayani"
    ],
    "correctOption": "General Syed Asim Munir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its rich natural resources, including coal and minerals?",
    "options": [
      "Balochistan",
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Balochistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Pakistan's national cricket team captain?",
    "options": [
      "Babar Azam",
      "Sarfaraz Ahmed",
      "Shoaib Malik",
      "Wasim Akram"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Babar Azam"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is the capital of the country?",
    "options": [
      "Islamabad",
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Quetta"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Islamabad"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year did Pakistan become a republic?",
    "options": [
      "1956",
      "1947",
      "1965",
      "1971"
    ],
    "correctOption": "1956"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the founder of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
      "Allama Iqbal",
      "Liaquat Ali Khan",
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which political party is led by Shehbaz Sharif?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Muslim League (N)",
      "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)",
      "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)",
      "Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Muslim League (N)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organization is responsible for conducting elections in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Election Commission of Pakistan",
      "Supreme Court of Pakistan",
      "National Assembly",
      "Senate"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Election Commission of Pakistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest dam in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Tarbela Dam",
      "Mangla Dam",
      "Chashma Dam",
      "Bhasha Dam"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Tarbela Dam"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its tea gardens?",
    "options": [
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Gilgit-Baltistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader served as the Prime Minister before Imran Khan?",
    "options": [
      "Shahid Khaqan Abbasi",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Pervez Musharraf",
      "Yousaf Raza Gillani"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Shahid Khaqan Abbasi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known as the cultural capital of the country?",
    "options": [
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Islamabad",
      "Peshawar"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the famous annual event held in Karachi celebrating literature and arts?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi Literature Festival",
      "Lahore Literary Festival",
      "Islamabad Book Fair",
      "Peshawar Arts Festival"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karachi Literature Festival"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is the most populous?",
    "options": [
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Punjab"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which institution is responsible for Pakistan's foreign policy?",
    "options": [
      "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
      "Supreme Court",
      "National Assembly",
      "Senate"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize?",
    "options": [
      "Malala Yousafzai",
      "Abdul Sattar Edhi",
      "Benazir Bhutto",
      "Imran Khan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Malala Yousafzai"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Pakistan's largest seaport?",
    "options": [
      "Gwadar Port",
      "Karachi Port",
      "Qasim Port",
      "Port Qasim"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Gwadar Port"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the current Chief Justice of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Omar Ata Bandial",
      "Asif Saeed Khosa",
      "Mian Saqib Nisar",
      "Iftikhar Muhammad Chaudhry"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Omar Ata Bandial"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was known for the slogan 'Roti, Kapra aur Makaan'?",
    "options": [
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Benazir Bhutto",
      "Imran Khan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani film industry?",
    "options": [
      "Lollywood",
      "Bollywood",
      "Hollywood",
      "Kollywood"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lollywood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city hosted the 2022 Commonwealth Games?",
    "options": [
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Islamabad",
      "Quetta"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani national airline?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan International Airlines (PIA)",
      "Emirates",
      "Qatar Airways",
      "Etihad Airways"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan International Airlines (PIA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani political party is led by Bilawal Bhutto Zardari?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)",
      "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)",
      "Pakistan Muslim League (N)",
      "Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani highest civil award?",
    "options": [
      "Nishan-e-Pakistan",
      "Sitara-e-Shujaat",
      "Hilal-e-Pakistan",
      "Tamgha-e-Imtiaz"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Nishan-e-Pakistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani university is known for its excellence in engineering and technology?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS)",
      "University of the Punjab",
      "Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS)",
      "National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is famous for its historical site Mohenjo-Daro?",
    "options": [
      "Sindh",
      "Punjab",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Sindh"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the 'Father of the Pakistani Nuclear Program'?",
    "options": [
      "Abdul Qadeer Khan",
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "Pervez Musharraf",
      "Benazir Bhutto"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Abdul Qadeer Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province has the largest number of national parks?",
    "options": [
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known as the 'City of Gardens'?",
    "options": [
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Islamabad",
      "Peshawar"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest hospital in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Jinnah Postgraduate Medical Centre",
      "Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital",
      "Khyber Teaching Hospital",
      "Liaquat University of Medical and Health Sciences"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Jinnah Postgraduate Medical Centre"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the current Governor of Punjab?",
    "options": [
      "Mohsin Naqvi",
      "Chaudhry Sarwar",
      "Raja Basharat",
      "Sardar Usman Buzdar"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Mohsin Naqvi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani political party is known for its symbol of a 'bat'?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)",
      "Pakistan Muslim League (N)",
      "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)",
      "Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest glacier in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Siachen Glacier",
      "Baltoro Glacier",
      "Biafo Glacier",
      "Hispar Glacier"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Siachen Glacier"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani cricketer is known as 'Sultan of Swing'?",
    "options": [
      "Wasim Akram",
      "Shoaib Akhtar",
      "Imran Khan",
      "Javed Miandad"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Wasim Akram"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first woman Prime Minister of Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Benazir Bhutto",
      "Fatima Jinnah",
      "Hina Rabbani Khar",
      "Sherry Rehman"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Benazir Bhutto"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Pakistan's largest river?",
    "options": [
      "Indus River",
      "Chenab River",
      "Jhelum River",
      "Ravi River"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Indus River"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its famous landmark, the Badshahi Mosque?",
    "options": [
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Islamabad",
      "Rawalpindi"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani political party led by Asif Ali Zardari?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)",
      "Pakistan Muslim League (N)",
      "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)",
      "Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its scenic beauty and mountains?",
    "options": [
      "Gilgit-Baltistan",
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Gilgit-Baltistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was known for the slogan 'Vote for Change'?",
    "options": [
      "Imran Khan",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Benazir Bhutto",
      "Asif Ali Zardari"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Imran Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani sports league for cricket?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Super League (PSL)",
      "Indian Premier League (IPL)",
      "Big Bash League (BBL)",
      "Caribbean Premier League (CPL)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Super League (PSL)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its IT industry and software development?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi",
      "Lahore",
      "Islamabad",
      "Rawalpindi"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its cultural diversity and traditional festivals?",
    "options": [
      "Sindh",
      "Punjab",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Sindh"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was known for the slogan 'Aik Naya Pakistan'?",
    "options": [
      "Imran Khan",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "Benazir Bhutto"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Imran Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani national educational testing service?",
    "options": [
      "National Testing Service (NTS)",
      "Educational Testing Service (ETS)",
      "Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education (BISE)",
      "University of the Punjab"
    ],
    "correctOption": "National Testing Service (NTS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was awarded the Nishan-e-Haider posthumously?",
    "options": [
      "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti",
      "General Ayub Khan",
      "General Zia-ul-Haq",
      "General Pervez Musharraf"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani highest civilian award?",
    "options": [
      "Nishan-e-Pakistan",
      "Hilal-e-Pakistan",
      "Sitara-e-Shujaat",
      "Tamgha-e-Imtiaz"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Nishan-e-Pakistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its financial and commercial activities?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi",
      "Lahore",
      "Islamabad",
      "Peshawar"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karachi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the founder of the Pakistani political party Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI)?",
    "options": [
      "Imran Khan",
      "Pervez Musharraf",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Benazir Bhutto"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Imran Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for the historical site of Mohenjo-Daro?",
    "options": [
      "Sindh",
      "Punjab",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Sindh"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was the country's first military ruler?",
    "options": [
      "General Ayub Khan",
      "General Zia-ul-Haq",
      "Pervez Musharraf",
      "General Ashfaq Pervez Kayani"
    ],
    "correctOption": "General Ayub Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its beautiful lakes and valleys?",
    "options": [
      "Muree",
      "Karimabad",
      "Peshawar",
      "Quetta"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karimabad"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani national television network?",
    "options": [
      "Pakistan Television Corporation (PTV)",
      "Express News",
      "Geo News",
      "Dawn News"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pakistan Television Corporation (PTV)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader was known for the slogan 'Roti, Kapra aur Makaan'?",
    "options": [
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "Nawaz Sharif",
      "Benazir Bhutto",
      "Imran Khan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its vibrant arts and music scene?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi",
      "Lahore",
      "Islamabad",
      "Rawalpindi"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karachi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its rich cultural heritage and historic monuments?",
    "options": [
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Balochistan",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Punjab"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani leader served as the Chief Martial Law Administrator before becoming President?",
    "options": [
      "General Zia-ul-Haq",
      "General Pervez Musharraf",
      "General Ayub Khan",
      "General Yahya Khan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "General Zia-ul-Haq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its historical landmark, the Lahore Fort?",
    "options": [
      "Lahore",
      "Karachi",
      "Islamabad",
      "Rawalpindi"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Lahore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is home to the ancient city of Taxila?",
    "options": [
      "Punjab",
      "Sindh",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Punjab"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani annual festival celebrating the Sindhi culture?",
    "options": [
      "Sindh Festival",
      "Lahore Arts Festival",
      "Karachi Cultural Festival",
      "Peshawar Literary Festival"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Sindh Festival"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the current Federal Minister for Finance in Pakistan?",
    "options": [
      "Ishaq Dar",
      "Asad Umar",
      "Shaukat Tarin",
      "Hafeez Sheikh"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Ishaq Dar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani province is known for its traditional crafts and embroidery?",
    "options": [
      "Sindh",
      "Punjab",
      "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "Balochistan"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Sindh"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Pakistani city is known for its famous annual event, the Karachi International Book Fair?",
    "options": [
      "Karachi",
      "Lahore",
      "Islamabad",
      "Peshawar"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Karachi"
  }
]

